<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>en.ergie.at</title><link>/en/</link><description>Recent content on en.ergie.at</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; AIT Austrian Institute of Technology GmbH</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:47:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Balancing Groups</title><link>/en/wissen/bilanzgruppen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:40:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>/en/wissen/bilanzgruppen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Balancing groups are central elements in the Austrian electricity market, ensuring that electricity consumption and generation remain balanced. In case of unforeseen deviations, imbalance settlement is used to cover the difference. This article provides an overview of how balancing groups work and their importance for grid stability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Actors and Stakeholders</title><link>/en/wissen/akteure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:01:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/en/wissen/akteure/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Austrian energy system is based on complex interactions between various actors who ensure grid stability, energy distribution, and market regulation. Specialized institutions work closely together, from controlling electricity flows to billing energy consumption data. This article provides an overview of who these actors are and the roles they play.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Austrian Electricity Grid</title><link>/en/wissen/stromnetz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 11:51:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>/en/wissen/stromnetz/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Austrian electricity grid forms the foundation for the transport of electrical energy from power plants to end consumers. It consists of seven grid levels, which differ in their functions and voltage levels, and are organized by transmission and distribution system operators. This article provides an overview of the different grid levels and their respective roles in the electricity grid.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Merit-Order</title><link>/knowledge/merit-order/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:49:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>/knowledge/merit-order/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Merit Order determines the sequence in which power plants are used for electricity generation. This article provides insight into how this order influences electricity prices and the role different energy sources play in the process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Topics</title><link>/en/themen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 21:40:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>/en/themen/</guid><description>&lt;p>An overview of various topics is being created here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>/en/impressum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:47:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>/en/impressum/</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="relative group">Imprint
&lt;div id="imprint" class="anchor">&lt;/div>
&lt;span
class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
&lt;a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#imprint" aria-label="Anchor">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This page is currently under construction. For now, we refer to &lt;a href="https://www.ait.ac.at/impressum" target="_blank">ait.ac.at/impressum&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>